Allahu Akbar Allahu Akbar Allahu Akbar Allahu Akbar La Elaha Ella Allah
La Elaha Ella Allah
Alhamdu Lillah, Wa Ash-hadu Alla Elaha Ella Allah Wahdahu La Shareeka Lah.
We praise God and we bear witness that there is only One God,
Allah.
I want to talk today about the whole idea behind our existence here.
It is very important to define our goals.
The distinction between God's kingdom
and Satan's kingdom
is the whole idea
in this world.
We read in the prayer
that God is مَـٰلِكِ يَوْمِ ٱلدِّينِ
God is the Master of the Day of Judgment
the eternal Day of Judgment.
And it is because God has given permission to Satan to set up a kingdom
in this tiny tiny spec in God's dominion, the planet Earth,
to show him that he is not competent
to be a god besides God
which is the thought that crossed his mind.
So, the whole idea is that this is a test for Satan
to show that in God's kingdom, there is perfect happiness.
And I mean by perfect happiness, perfect health, perfect wealth, perfect joy.
Satan's kingdom is plagued with problem.
So, this is, this is what I want you to remember
always that the distinction, the whole idea is a distinction between God's kingdom and Satan's kingdom
that God's kingdom has no problems
once you pass all the required tests
and once you come to the point, this point of perfection, when you are in God's kingdom.
And that Satan's kingdom is plagued with problems.
Our soul grows and develops
and this constitutes the secret of perfect happiness in this world
as you see on the wall there. That's the theme of the new translation.
The secret of happiness in this world is a fed, nourished soul.
You ate breakfast today, or lunch, or snack or something. You ate something today. You gave your body something today.
And the people who did not feed their soul, they have a starving soul
without feeling the pain.
The pain will show up all at once
when the separation happens between the body and the soul.
Right now the soul is obscured by the body
and the pangs of starvation and pain and hunger are not felt.
It is felt later on when it is too late
and when it is eternal and when it is called Hell.
So, the whole idea is setting up a distinction between God's kingdom and Satan's kingdom.
How do we join God's kingdom?
We have to do things that are ordered by God.
We have to follow the commandments and abstain from the prohibitions.
It's very simple
It's listed in the Old Testament, the New Testament, and the Final Testament, the Quran.
Remember the famous statement, when in the new testament somebody went to Jesus and told him how do I attain salvation?
And Jesus said follow the commandments.
A very simple instruction.
And now the commandments are listed in detail
with a built-in proof telling you this is from God.
This is what you should do for your own good
and this is what you should not do for your own good.
This is how you join God's kingdom.
If you don't,
you will have a starving soul, a shrunk, weak
unnourished soul
that cannot be happy no matter how much the body achieves
of money or fame or whatever, success.
We can join God's kingdom anytime we want to.
It's wide open.
And you can join it right now
in order to guarantee this perfect happiness.
You guarantee success in this world
where no problems, no headaches, no diseases.
We can do this anytime. Anybody can do this anytime.
And after you join, for a while, there is a period when you may step out of God's kingdom
And then God pinches you, if H. loves you, if He cares about you and you come running right back to God's kingdom
but as long as you are inside God's kingdom, there is perfect happiness.
You'll be in God's kingdom only if you know God,
recognize God, believe in God, as He is
mainly, the most important point that He is doing everything.
That everything is done in accordance with His will
that God is doing everything.
It boils down to this statement.
It is much too complicated for most people to understand.
But you must know that. If you know God, you'll know that He is doing everything.
Then, nobody will bother you.
Your supervisor at work will not bother you because he's not doing anything.
And you will look at him whether he is promoting you or reprimanding you, as God's work.
And if you're perfectly in God's kingdom, you know that whatever is happening is for your own good.
You'll understand it and you will be perfectly happy.
So, we can join God's kingdom right now through something that's called repentance.
You can make a pledge right now
that you will join God's kingdom, you will be firmly in God's kingdom
that you will follow His commandments
not because you're doing Him a favor
because you are doing you a favor.
You can pledge to join God's kingdom right now
by doing the five prayers
because you need it,
because you need to feed your soul.
The Quran makes a very important point on showing off.
Some people may pray
because they are showing off
or some people may not pray because of peer pressure.
They're embarrassed to pray in front of their friends.
So, what this person is doing is he's cheating himself.
It's exactly like eating continuously no-calorie food for the body.
If you eat no-calorie food exclusively, you cannot live.
Your body will die.
And the same with the soul.
We cannot cheat ourselves by showing off
or by not praying because of peer pressure
or because we are embarrassed from our friends.
You will never be embarrassed, too embarrassed to eat lunch or dinner or breakfast.
So, your body is getting its rights fully
but not the soul, if you are affected by peer pressure or showing off.
So, when I say repent now, I want collectively, all of us to join God's kingdom,
that we are going to pledge to be in God's kingdom for our own good that we're going...
You wanna pledge that you will never tell a lie,
you will never sin
and you mean it,
as of now
that you will be in God's kingdom
you'll carry out the five nourishing meals for your soul
that you will follow the commandments in the Quran
you're gonna fast the month of Ramadan
which comes April 17, by the way
you must be ready as of now
that you'll not backbite anybody
you will not hurt anyone
unless they are fighting in the cause of God which doesn't happen here.
This is a free land.
Simply, that you will follow the commandments
and you make this solemn pledge now.
God says there is a commandment in the Quran that says
يَـٰٓأَيُّهَا ٱلَّذِينَ ءَامَنُوا۟
O, you who believe,
this is directed to those who believe
تُوبُوٓا۟ إِلَى ٱللَّهِ
Repent to God, meaning enter into a covenant with God
تَوْبَةً نَّصُوحًا
means irrevocable repentance.
Irrevocable, irrevocable, so you mean it
as you repent now and as you pledge now
to enter God's kingdom and attain perfect happiness
and God will believe you, will take your word for it. When you make a Covenant,
He will accept the Covenant.
and God says in the Quran
أَوْفُوا بِعَهْدِي أُوفِ بِعَهْدِكُمْ
You carry out your part of the Covenant, I will carry out my part of the Covenant.
which is this: the Perfect Happiness.
So, we are going now collectively to make a Covenant,
enter into a Covenant with God that we will repent
that as of now, there will be no sin
that you're gonna be a perfect human being.
And then you're gonna keep your part of the Covenant.
Tooboo Ela Allah.
Alhamdu Lillah, Wa Ash-hadu Alla Elaha Ella Allah Wahdahu La Shareeka Lah.
We praise God and we bear witness that there is no other god besides Him.
Congratulations! We probably shook the galaxy
just this group of us
pledging, entering into a Covenant with God
and God accepts you with open arms.
As we recite Al-Fãtehah in the prayers,
we say Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem.
Arrahman Arraheem, Most Gracious, Most Merciful.
And God's mercy is beyond our imagination.
God is Merciful beyond our imagination.
And I feel this a lot with the discovering, discovering the Quran.
For example, you tell the human beings
when we learn that Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala gives the human being 40 years
to make up his or her mind
40 years of research, looking around, studying and then, deciding,
people say no, what do you mean 40 years? That's too long.
Because people are mean.
They are not as merciful as God.
Many people I tell them a person who dies at the age of 35
and he didn't pray, he didn't fast, he didn't do anything
is going to Heaven.
They say no, send him to Hell.
Why does he go to Heaven? you know
But God is Merciful beyond our wildest imagination.
And God decided that He wants to give us 40 years
to look around and study
and thank God, you know, thinking of myself
and many other, my friends who barely made it, you know
before the 40 years were up.
God is Merciful
because we would be in deep trouble if it was shorter than 40 years.
There is a law in Quran that says Equivalence, the law of QESAS Equivalence
is detailed in the Quran. It goes beyond what was dictated in the Torah.
And it says the male for the male, the female for the female
the slave for the slave, the free for the free.
And this restricts Capital Punishment
and this is followed by recommendation to substitute compensation for capital punishment
but when I ask the people, even the gentlest and kindest of friends
and you tell them a male killed a female
What is the punishment? They say kill him.
Why? God says the male for the male, the female for the female.
So, He's given us... where do you get the male for the female?
I say a female killed a male.
What is the punishment for this murder? They say kill her. Kill her.
Why? I mean, you look at the law
but when I discuss it with them and they look at the Quran,
they see that God's Mercy is there
and we cannot violate these laws.
We are mean.
God's Mercy is beyond our wildest imagination.
This verse the male for the male, the female for the female and so on is followed at the end of the verse
(2:178) مَنِ ٱعْتَدَىٰ بَعْدَ ذَٰلِكَ فَلَهُۥ عَذَابٌ أَلِيمٌۭ
Anyone who transgresses this law
after this
which indicates this is a new law
بَعْدَ ذَٰلِكَ
after this
will suffer a painful retribution.
So, it is very clear in the verse.
And everyone that we discussed this matter with, they agreed finally with the Quran. They could see God's Mercy there
that the verse leans favorably towards compensation
rather than capital punishment.
So, God's Mercy Arrahman Arraheem is beyond our imagination
and we must...
I'm gonna go into another subject now
and this is how do you act on behalf of your friends?
You have a very dear friend
and somebody says something unkind about your friend,
what do you do?
You just sit and take it, you and your friend?
Or do you defend your friend?
If you know
that your friend is not a cheater, for example
and somebody tell you that this friend of yours is a cheater,
you will become upset on behalf of your friend
and you will defend your friend. You say no, he's not a cheater.
So, I come from a background with a lot of garbage that I must get rid of.
We all do.
And God teaches us through examples.
When brother, Dr. Mansour, mentioned in one KHUTBA that
the thing that we all came from, we all believed this at one time
that God ordered Abraham to kill his son,
his only son.
We learn from our research and looking in the Quran in detail
that the Quran NEVER says that God ordered Ibrahim to kill his son.
There is a law in Quran that God does not command vice.
(7:28) إِنَّ اللهَ‌ لا يَأْمُرُ بِالْفَحْشاءِ
This is a rule.
And God's mercy
will... with this... with knowing this about God's Mercy, do you think He will tell somebody go kill your son, your only son?
You know, I expected many of us
to go to Dr. Mansour, for example, and say
we studied, we did research, we looked in the Quran and we discovered that God NEVER told Ibrahim to kill his son.
You must stand up for your friend. God wants solid friends
who will not take any statement that contradicts God's qualities.
If somebody accuses you of being a cheat
and you are in a position of power, you are forming a cabinet, for example, a government
and you are a president of some company, chairman of the board or something
and you know that this person, even though he or she loves you,
thinks wrongly that you are a cheat.
How will you act towards this person?
If you think of God that He commanded somebody to kill his son
an act of vicious, merciless, a command,
How will He feel about you on the Day of Judgement, if you feel that way?
I discussed this matter with Dr. Mansour
and we looked in the Quran and he said:
that's right. He read the verses.
and it said
(37:102) إِنِّىٓ أَرَىٰ فِى ٱلْمَنَامِ أَنِّىٓ أَذْبَحُكَ
I see in a dream that I am slaughtering you.
And he said that's right.
God didn't order Ibrahim to kill his son.
It doesn't say that in the Quran anywhere.
(37:105) يَـٰٓإِبْرَٰهِيمُ (37:104) قَدْ صَدَّقْتَ ٱلرُّءْيَآ
You believed your dream.
if you look at it,
but you see what they put in our heads as we were growing up, all of us
and it comes from some distortions in the Bible
that God ordered Ibrahim to take your son and kill him.
And it affected all of us
but we have to look in the Quran
and derive our information from the Quran.
And had God ordered Ibrahim to kill his son,
He will tell us
but He wouldn't
because God put the rule. He said He does not command فحشا , vice,
gross matters.
God will not be afraid to tell us
if He did do that.
I will accept it if He did do that.
But He didn't. God's Mercy is beyond our wildest dreams.
Ibrahim thought that he received the command from God in that dream
but you see the crime is magnified because they tell us that the dream of the prophet is truth
which makes them not human.
I mean, it turns into idolization of the prophets.
So, it's a gross crime from many many angles.
There's a few other things that I need to say about this.
Let me see if I remember.
I know there's something that I'm forgetting to say.
So, maybe, I'll remember it in the prayer.
It has to do with Ibrahim thinking
that he was killing his son.
So he went ahead,
God intervened.
It's exactly the other way around.
I mean, it's contrary to what most people believe.
God only intervened to save Ismail,
Ibrahim's son.
So, not only He did not order Ibrahim to kill his son, He intervened to save the son
because Ibrahim was a sincere believer.
He was in God's kingdom.
And God will not not let him.
God will not allow you to fall in sin.
God will not allow you to do something wrong when you're in His kingdom.
He will not allow you. He will not let you do it.
And you made the pledge, you are in God's kingdom.